DAKOTA LEROY

UI/UX DESIGN AND RESEARCH

SUMMARY

I am a graduate of Tufts University with a B.S. in Computer Science with one year worth of professional experience in UI/UX design and research. I am currently looking for full time time employment as a UI/UX Designer or Product Designer in the Boston area.

SKILLS

DESIGN: User Research, Prototyping, Usability Testing, Wireframing, Basic Color Theory, User Interviewing

SOFTWARE: Sketch, Axure RP, Adobe Xd, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe InDesign, InVision, GitHub, lira

LANGUAGES: CSS, HTML, JavaScript, React, Python, Java

EDUCATION

Tufts University

B.S. Computer Science 2019
Concentration in UX Design and Research

Miss Porter's School High School Diploma 2015

CONTACT

- ☑ Dakota.LeRoy126@gmail.com
- dakotaleroy.github.io
- **** 2038059486
- **♀** Boston, MA

in /dakota-leroy-725bb5126/

dakotaleroy

EMPLOYMENT

Liberty Mutual

Boston, MA

Sept. 2019 to Current

UI/UX Technology Associate

- Shadowing other UX designers within the company, attending events about various topics in UX, and learning about the future of design at Liberty
- Conducting user interviews with stakeholders to identify workflow issues in various UI screens and having debriefs with the engineering team to discuss the findings and develop solutions
- Designing and demoing mockups, wireframes, and prototypes of updated UIs for SafeCo Insurance Comp2.0 to improve the experience of the insurance agents who use the compensation platform

Medidata Solutions

New York, NY June 2018 to Aug. 2018

Software Engineering Intern

- Developed the Platform Workflow Tracker, a Rails web application which sends and collects data from Zipkin (a distributed tracing system), to track internal performance metrics for Medidata's platform services
- Built an rspec testing suite for Platform Workflow Tracker in Rails while on an Agile team that focused on authorization and authentication
- Designed and documented how information would be stored and accessed in the database, and how the application would communicate with Zipkin to consume its data

Cisco Cambridge, MA UI/UX Intern May 2017 to Aug. 2017

- Improved the existing UI of Cisco Defense Orchestrator, Cisco's internet security firewall management system, using Sketch to create redesigns for aspects of the product's interface
- Designed mockups and wireframes for new features as part of an Agile team working towards scaling up the product's device management capabilities
- Ensured the technical feasibility of UX designs by working closely with the head UX designer and enhanced user workflows by participating in user testing process

PROJECTS

Rejected Transactions

Winter 2020

I worked as the UX lead on my team to improve the usability of the Rejected Transactions screen on SalesComp 2.0, an internal sales and compensation tool for SafeCo Insurance. I conducted user interviews with stakeholders, drew wire frames, created a fully interactive prototype, and demoed the new screen back to stakeholders. **Skills**: User interviews, Axure RP, Prototyping

pet.me Winter 2020

I designed an iPhone pet cam application for users to manage their pet camera. I did research into what current workflows look like for similar applications and then designed my own UI for a mobile application that connects to an in-home camera with capabilities to interact with your pet.

Skills: Adobe Xd, Adobe Illustrator, UI design

Roomie Fall 2019

I designed the UI for an online portal system for tenants to use in conjunction with their property managers. I found inspiration by focusing on solving the current problems facing users on my own property management's current website.

Skills: Adobe Xd, UI design, User research

Breakfast of Champions

Winter 2019

Given a dataset of random breakfast foods, I chose a target audience (women recovering from disordered eating) and designed a table and related infographic that offered information about these foods in a way that would appeal for this specific audience.

Skills: Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, User research

TEMS vs. College Student

Fall 2018

I was a UI/UX lead on this project and designed many of the user interfaces and all of the characters for this 2D action game. Additionally, I designed and created the game's website.

Skills: Adobe Photoshop, CSS, HTML, Git, Unity, User testing

NavGator Spring 2017

I was the UX designer on a web development team for this project. I designed the project's UI and helped to implement the front-end of this navigational Heroku app game.

Skills: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Heroku, Github, UI design